# **Connor Folk**

(704) 651-2854
<a href="mailto:cafolk@ncsu.edu">cafolk@ncsu.edu</a>
<a href="https://connorfolk.github.io/Projects">https://connorfolk.github.io/Projects</a>

#### **OVERVIEW**

Passionate, personable, adaptable, and dedicated to understanding, diagnosing, and solving complex client problems through data analysis. Experience in a variety of technical and soft skills including:

- Data wrangling
- Time series

Technical communication

- Data visualization
- Data mining

Collaboration

- Linear/logistic regression
- Machine learning

### Relationship building

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S. in Analytics

May 2022

Institute for Advanced Analytics, NC State University, Raleigh, NC

# B.A. in Economics with Minors in Statistics and Entrepreneurship

May 2021

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC

Honors: Graduated with Highest Distinction, Phi Beta Kappa, and Omicron Delta Epsilon

#### Study Abroad: Development and International Economics

Summer 2019

London School of Economics, London, UK

## **PRACTICUM PROJECT**

Visionist Columbia, MD

#### **Program Liaison**

September 2021—Present

- Utilize event data of interactions between socio-political actors to aid in the understanding of complex global entity relationships
- Develop dynamic network visualizations to identify key actors, threats, and partnerships
- Leverage time series and survival analysis to model intervention impacts on network relationships and to predict time-to-conflict
- Implement Agile methodology for effective project management

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Chapel Hill, NC

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant

November 2020–May 2021

- Scraped, cleaned, and transformed revenue data into price indexes using R
- Identified bull and bear markets in 49 different sectors of the economy using the "bbdetection" package
- Visualized the different markets to analyze trends in dates, durations, and amplitudes of each bull and bear market in a beamer presentation

#### **Undergraduate Learning Assistant**

August 2020-May 2021

- Explained technical topics, including Classical, Keynesian, and Open Economy economic models
- Developed ways to facilitate student learning in intermediate macroeconomic theory
- Oversaw lectures of over 200 students and led discussions in breakout rooms

# Business Consulting Intern for Substantial Magazine

Remote Summer 2020

 Modeled magazine, website, and newsletter advertising prices of competitors in Microsoft Excel to optimize the company's ad pricing model

- Compared revenue streams from different subscriber pricing models to maximize profit
- Communicated recommendations to key stakeholders, including the CEO and major investor

### **SKILLS**

District C

- Languages: R, Python, SQL, SAS
- Certification: SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming Using SAS 9.4